Guide to the K. Leroy Irvis Papers, 1946-1995 AIS.1971.06
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Community, 1945-2005; VII.
  - Community Involvement (2010 addition), 1947-2005; 4.
    - Governor's Sports and Exposition Facilities Task Force, 1996 (Box 104, Folder 55)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Literary Council, 1988 (Box 104, Folder 56)
    - Green for State Assembly, 1980 (Box 104, Folder 57)
    - Hamilton School, 1981 (Box 104, Folder 58)
    - Harper, Ruth B., State Representative, 1992 (Box 104, Folder 59)
    - Harrah's Entertainment, 1996 (Box 104, Folder 60)
    - Harris Learning Center, 1976 (Box 104, Folder 61)
    - Harrisburg Area Community College, undated (Box 104, Folder 62)
    - Harrisburg School District, undated (Box 104, Folder 63)
    - Heinz History Center Tribute, undated (Box 104, Folder 64)
    - H. John Heinz III Public Policy Symposium, 1993 (Box 104, Folder 65)
    - H. John Heinz III School of Public Policy and Management, 1992 (Box 104, Folder 66)
    - Howard Heinz Endowment, 1990-1991 (Box 104, Folder 67)
    - Vira I. Heinz Endowment, 1990 (Box 104, Folder 68)
    - Heinz Family Foundation, 1993 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Hillman State Park Conservation, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Historical Society of Western Pennsylvania, 1992 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - History Makers, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - History Makers, 2005 (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Home Rule Charter, 1995-1996 (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Homer S. Brown Legacy, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 7)
    - Hudson Valley Girl Scout Council, 1987 (Box 105, Folder 8)
    - Human Relations, 1968, 1995 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Industry Day, 1984 (Box 105, Folder 10)
    - Interfaith Volunteer Caregivers, 1997 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - International Year of Older Persons, 1999 (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - Investing Now, 1990 (Box 105, Folder 13)
    - Irvis Video Project, undated (Box 105, Folder 14)
    - Judge Genevieve Blatt Endowment Fund, 1996 (Box 105, Folder 15)
    - K. Leroy Irvis Minority Public Affairs Program Project Concept, 1994 (Box 105, Folder 16)
    - Kennedy-Lawrence Annual Dinner, 1978, 1981 (Box 105, Folder 17)
    - Knoll, Catherine-Baker, 1987-1988 (Box 105, Folder 18)
    - Kury Campaign, 1996 (Box 105, Folder 19)
    - Kutztown University, 1997 (Box 105, Folder 20)
    - Lincoln Portrait, 1991 (Box 105, Folder 21)
    - Lincoln University, 1989-1993 (Box 105, Folder 22)
    - Lincoln University ACT 101/TIME, 1999 (Box 105, Folder 23)
    - Magee-Women's Health Foundation, 1992 (Box 105, Folder 24)
    - Martin Luther King Jr., 1983, 1993 (Box 105, Folder 25)
    - Martin Luther King Jr. Cultural Center, 1992 (Box 105, Folder 26)
    - Masons, 1995 (Box 105, Folder 27)
    - Mass, 1974 (Box 105, Folder 28)
    - McDonald, Valerie A., 1997 (Box 105, Folder 29)
    - Medical, Health Spirit, 1980 (Box 105, Folder 30)
    - Mini-White House Conference on Aging, 1994 (Box 105, Folder 31)
    - Montefiore Hospital, 1988 (Box 105, Folder 32)
    - NAACP, 1977, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 33)
    - National Association of Social Workers, 1995 (Box 105, Folder 34)
    - National Visionary Leadership Project, 2006 (Box 105, Folder 35)
    - Neighborhood Platform Conference, undated (Box 105, Folder 36)
    - Nursing Recruitment Coalition, 1991 (Box 105, Folder 37)
    - Oakland Preservation, 1991 (Box 105, Folder 38)
    - Opera America, 1980-1981 (Box 105, Folder 39)
    - Pamphlets, African American Interests, 1968-1999 (Box 105, Folder 40)
    - Pamphlets, Art, 1981-2001 (Box 105, Folder 41)
    - Pamphlets, Community Development, 1976-2000 (Box 105, Folder 42)
    - Pamphlets, Legislative/Political, 1969-2005 (Box 105, Folder 43)
    - Pamphlets, Miscellaneous, 1957-2002 (Box 105, Folder 44)
    - Pamphlets, Music, 1947-1998 (Box 105, Folder 45)
    - Pamphlets, Personal, 1966-1998 (Box 105, Folder 46)
    - Pamphlets, Religious, 1976-1999 (Box 105, Folder 47)
    - Pennsylvania AFL-CIO, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 48)
    - Pennsylvania Art Education Association, 1996 (Box 105, Folder 49)
    - Pennsylvania Capitol Preservation Committee, 1994-2005 (Box 105, Folder 50)
    - Pennsylvania Citizens for Better Libraries, 1992-1995 (Box 105, Folder 51)
    - Pennsylvania Council on the Arts, undated (Box 105, Folder 52)
    - Pennsylvania Director's Association for Community Action, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 53)
    - Pennsylvania Public Television Network Commission, 1975 (Box 105, Folder 54)
    - Personal Assistance, 1980-1987 (Box 105, Folder 55)
    - Philadelphia Civic Center, 1979-1980 (Box 105, Folder 56)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1990-1992 (Box 105, Folder 57)
    - Philadelphia Foundation, undated (Box 105, Folder 58)
    - The Pierans, Inc., 1995 (Box 105, Folder 59)
    - The Pierans, Art Awareness, 1989 (Box 105, Folder 60)
    - Pirates, 1995 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Pittsburgh, 1980-1993 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - Pittsburgh Brag Book, 2000 (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - Pittsburgh Center for the Arts, 1992-1995 (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - Pittsburgh Conference for Replication of the Ex-Offenders Program, 1980 (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Pittsburgh Courier, 1981 (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - Poetry Editing, undated (Box 106, Folder 7)
    - Portrait of a Speaker, 1989 (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - Preserving Pittsburgh, 1994 (Box 106, Folder 9)
    - Program to Aid Citizen Enterprise (PACE), 1998 (Box 106, Folder 10)
    - Project 90, 1995 (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - Public Art Committee, 2000, 2005 (Box 106, Folder 12)
    - Public Participation Committee, 1989 (Box 106, Folder 13)
    - Public Transportation, undated (Box 106, Folder 14)
    - Railroad Museum of Pennsylvania, 1988 (Box 106, Folder 15)
    - Resumes, undated (Box 106, Folder 16)
    - Rockefeller Institute, 1993 (Box 106, Folder 17)
    - Shadyside Academy, 1970 (Box 106, Folder 18)
    - Sickle Cell Society Inc., 1992-2004 (Box 106, Folder 19)
    - Singel Campaign, undated (Box 106, Folder 20)
    - Slippery Rock State College, 1976 (Box 106, Folder 21)
    - Slippery Rock University, undated (Box 106, Folder 22)
    - Southdown Inc., 1991 (Box 106, Folder 23)
    - State Museum of Pennsylvania, 1993 (Box 106, Folder 24)
    - SUNY Albany, 1986-2002 (Box 106, Folder 25)
    - SUNY Albany Magazine, 2005 (Box 106, Folder 26)
    - Temple University, 1990-1995 (Box 106, Folder 27)
    - Temple University Alumni Magazine, 1986 (Box 106, Folder 28)
    - Temple University Institute of African and African American Affairs, 1988-1989 (Box 106, Folder 29)
    - Temple University Institute of African and African American Affairs, 1989 (Box 106, Folder 30)
    - Temple University, North Philadelphia Community Resource Guide, undated (Box 106, Folder 31)
    - Temple University Public Policy, 1995-1996 (Box 106, Folder 32)
    - Three Rivers Improvement and Development Corporation, 1971-1972 (Box 106, Folder 33)
    - Tri-State Consortium, 1992 (Box 106, Folder 34)
    - Ujima, 2002 (Box 106, Folder 35)
    - Understanding the Oceans, 1979 (Box 106, Folder 36)
    - U.S. Constitutional Bicentennial, 1976 (Box 106, Folder 37)
    - U.S.S. Independence, 1988 (Box 106, Folder 38)
    - U.S.S. Pittsburgh, 1985 (Box 106, Folder 39)
    - Unity Center, Friend of Unity Award, 1974 (Box 106, Folder 40)
    - Unity Institute, 1977-1979 (Box 106, Folder 41)
    - Unity Institute, 1978-1979 (Box 106, Folder 42)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1992, 1996 (Box 106, Folder 43)
    - University of Pennsylvania, School of Veterinary Medicine, 1991-1992 (Box 106, Folder 44)
    - Urban Redevelopment Authority, undated (Box 106, Folder 45)
    - Verna D. Wolford Memorial Service, 1996 (Box 106, Folder 46)
    - What About Pittsburgh? Three Rivers Improvement and Development Corporation, 1972 (Box 106, Folder 47)
    - Vanguard Jaycees Chapter, 1973 (Box 106, Folder 48)
    - YWCA, 1981 (Box 106, Folder 49)
    - Youth Choral Festival, 2002 (Box 106, Folder 50)
  - Clarion Project (1995 addition), 1989-1992; 5.
    This subseries includes presentations, history, reports, correspondence, and news releases regarding the construction of a hazardous waste management facility in Mill Creek Township, Clarion County, Pa. These materials are arranged by subject.
    - Technology Evaluation, November 16, 1989 (Box 77, Folder 237)
    - Proposed Phase II Evaluation Report, March-May, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 238-239)
    - Conceptual Facility Design Review, April, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 240)
    - Conceptual Design Presentation, April, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 241)
    - Compliance History, March-May, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 242-243)
    - Candidate Sites for Hazardous Waste Management Facility, July, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 244)
    - Tier 1 Site Evaluation Report, August, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 245)
    - Tier 2 Soils, Geologic, Groundwater Investigation Work Plan, November, 1990 (Box 77, Folder 246)
    - Phase I Application, June, 1991 (Box 77, Folder 247)
    - Citizen Correspondence (Box 78, Folder 248)
    - Various Correspondence (Box 78, Folder 249)
    - Public Advisory Committee (Box 78, Folder 250-251)
    - Public Participation Committee (Box 78, Folder 252)
    - News Releases (Box 78, Folder 253)
    - All Fired Up: Burning Hazardous Waste in Cement Kilns, 1992 (Box 78, Folder 254)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 78, Folder 255)
  - Camp Hill Prison Riots (1995 addition), 1989-1990; 6.
    This subseries consists of materials related to the Camp Hill Prison Riots of October 1989. Inmates held the State Correctional Institute at Camp Hill for four days. There were no escapes, however, 138 corrections officers were injured and 17 more were held hostage. Seventy inmates were also injured and 14 buildings were destroyed. The resulting costs for police, rescue, repairs and cleanup ran into the millions and were paid by Pennsylvania taxpayers. Irvis was a member of the Governor's Commission to investigate the riots.
    - Governor's Commission on Riots- Final Report (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Governor's Commission on Riots- Correspondence, October, 1989 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Governor's Commission on Riots- Correspondence, November 1, 1989-November 9, 1989 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Governor's Commission on Riots- Correspondence, November 10, 1989-November 30, 1989 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Governor's Commission on Riots- Correspondence, December, 1989 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Governor's Commission on Riots- Correspondence, January, 1990-February, 1990 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Various Newsclippings, 1990 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Photographs of Camp Hill Prison (after the riot) (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - African American Interests (2010 addition), 1933-2005; 7.
    Irvis' interest in African American affairs began early upon his arrival in Pittsburgh in the 1940s. During this time, Irvis joined the Urban League of Pittsburgh and took part in demonstrations against discrimination in Pittsburgh department stores. The African American Interests subseries documents Irvis' involvement with organizations and the African American community. Irvis was involved with a number of organizations including the Afro-American Historical and Cultural Museum, the American Foundation for Negro Affairs, the Black Elected Officials Summit, the NAACP, the National Black Caucus of State Legislatures, the Pennsylvania Black Conference on Higher Education, the Pennsylvania Legislative Black Caucus, and the University of Pittsburgh as each corresponded to issues pertinent to the African American Community. Irvis' membership within these organizations has produced event and conference information, pamphlets, organization literature, news clippings, publications and flyers. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - A Better Chance Program, 1972 (Box 110, Folder 44)
    - African American Summit, 1999 (Box 110, Folder 45)
    - African American Hall of Fame Sculpture Garden, 1986 (Box 110, Folder 46)
    - African American Lawyers, 1994-1995 (Box 110, Folder 47)
    - African American Women, 2000 (Box 110, Folder 48)
    - African American Women for Political Change, 2002 (Box 110, Folder 49)
    - Afro-American Historical and Cultural Museum, 1990-1994 (Box 110, Folder 50)
    - Afro-American Historical and Cultural Museum, 1989-1992 (Box 110, Folder 51)
    - All African People's Revolutionary Party, 1989 (Box 110, Folder 52)
    - American Foundation for Negro Affairs, 1984 (Box 110, Folder 53)
    - American Heritage, 1992 (Box 110, Folder 54)
    - Apartheid, 1985 (Box 110, Folder 55)
    - April 4th Mobilization Committee, Pittsburgh Coalition to Stop the Atlanta Child Murders, 1981 (Box 110, Folder 56)
    - Architects, 1991 (Box 110, Folder 57)
    - Association for the Study of Afro-American Life and History, undated (Box 110, Folder 58)
    - Black Artists, undated (Box 110, Folder 59)
    - Black Caucus Review, 1983 (Box 110, Folder 60)
    - Black Contractors Association, undated (Box 110, Folder 61)
    - Black Culture, Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, undated (Box 110, Folder 62)
    - Black Elected Officials, 1988 (Box 110, Folder 63)
    - Black elected Officials Summit, 1995 (Box 110, Folder 64)
    - Black Extravaganza, 1996-2001 (Box 110, Folder 65)
    - Black History, 1990 (Box 110, Folder 66)
    - Black History Museum Committee, 1983 (Box 110, Folder 67)
    - Blacks in Pittsburgh, 1992 (Box 110, Folder 68)
    - Black Law Journal, 1974 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Black Law Journal, 1974 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Black Leadership and Community Conference, 1981 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Black Opinion Magazine, 2005 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Black Politics, 1972 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Black Revolutionary War Patriots Memorial, 1988 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Black Solidarity Fair, undated (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Black United Fund of Pennsylvania, 1988 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - BWPC, 1987, 1988 (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - Black Voters, 1987 (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - Bowen, Uvella S. Adkins, Temple University, 1993 (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, 1996 (Box 111, Folder 12)
    - Carving, undated (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - Civil Rights in Pittsburgh, undated (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - Commission on Human Rights, 1995 (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Commission on Minority Participation in Education and American Life, 1988 (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - Committee to Elect & Friends of Rufus Lynch, 1998 (Box 111, Folder 17)
    - CCAC, 1996, undated (Box 111, Folder 18)
    - Conference on Black Basic Education, 1980 (Box 111, Folder 19)
    - Conference on Black History, 1990 (Box 111, Folder 20)
    - Congressional Black Caucus Foundation Policy Review, 1994 (Box 111, Folder 21)
    - The Crisis, 1949 (Box 111, Folder 22)
    - Democratic National Committee, 1968, 1984 (Box 111, Folder 23)
    - Editorial, 1968 (Box 111, Folder 24)
    - Education of Black Americans, 1979 (Box 111, Folder 25)
    - Erie I Community Center, 1983 (Box 111, Folder 26)
    - Fact Sheets, 1980 (Box 111, Folder 27)
    - Figureheads, undated (Box 111, Folder 28)
    - Ghana, undated (Box 111, Folder 29)
    - Grolier Books, 1956 (Box 111, Folder 30)
    - Historical Society of Western Pennsylvania, 1997 (Box 111, Folder 31)
    - Homer S. Brown Law Association, 2001 (Box 111, Folder 32)
    - Housing Authority, 1991 (Box 111, Folder 33)
    - International Review of African American Art, 2000 (Box 111, Folder 34)
    - Inter-Racial Action Council of Pittsburgh, undated (Box 111, Folder 35)
    - Irvis, the Negro in the Civil War, 1933 (Box 111, Folder 36)
    - Journal of African American History, 2003 (Box 111, Folder 37)
    - Journal of Blacks in Higher Education, 1996 (Box 111, Folder 38)
    - Kuumba Trust, 1997 (Box 111, Folder 39)
    - Lincoln University, 1989 (Box 111, Folder 40)
    - Mandela, Nelson, 1990, 1991 (Box 111, Folder 41)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 111, Folder 42)
    - Martin Luther King Jr., 1988-2003 (Box 111, Folder 43)
    - MLK Jr. Photo Exhibit, Countdown to Eternity, undated (Box 111, Folder 44)
    - MLK Jr. Prayer Breakfast, 2001 (Box 111, Folder 45)
    - Minority Employment, 1980 (Box 111, Folder 46)
    - Minority Enterprise Corporation of Southwestern Pennsylvania, 1992-1996 (Box 111, Folder 47)
    - NAACP, 1993, 1997 (Box 111, Folder 48)
    - NAACP Bicentennial Calendar, 1976 (Box 111, Folder 49)
    - NAACP Events, 1980-1992 (Box 111, Folder 50)
    - NAACP Membership, 1978 (Box 111, Folder 51)
    - National Association of Black Journalists, Frank Bolden, 2003 (Box 111, Folder 52)
    - National Bar Association, 2001 (Box 111, Folder 53)
    - National Black Assembly, undated (Box 111, Folder 54)
    - National Black Caucus of State Legislators, 1985 (Box 111, Folder 55)
    - National Black Caucus of State Legislators, 1987 (Box 111, Folder 56)
    - National Black Caucus on the Black Aged, 1980 (Box 111, Folder 57)
    - National Database of Arts Organizations of Color, 1995 (Box 111, Folder 58)
    - National Society of Black Engineers, 1990 (Box 111, Folder 59)
    - News clippings, 1976-2000 (Box 111, Folder 60)
    - Newsletters, 1970-2005 (Box 111, Folder 61)
    - Notes, 1957-1959 (Box 111, Folder 62)
    - Pamphlets, 1977-2004 (Box 111, Folder 63)
    - Pan-African Association of America, 1995 (Box 111, Folder 64)
    - Pelosi Report, 2003 (Box 111, Folder 65)
    - Pennsylvania Black Conference on Higher Education, 1970-2000 (Box 111, Folder 66)
    - Pennsylvania Black Conference on Higher Education, 1994-1996 (Box 111, Folder 67)
    - Pennsylvania Black Conference on Higher Education, 1992-2000 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - Pennsylvania Black Conference on Higher Education, Journal, 1996 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Pennsylvania Black History Committee, undated (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Pennsylvania Black Legislators, 1985 (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - Pennsylvania Blackbook, 1981 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Pennsylvania Democratic State Committee, 1987 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - Pennsylvania Heritage, Black History and Culture, 1977-1978 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, 1968 (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - Pennsylvania Legislative Black Caucus, 1974-1998 (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - Pennsylvania Legislative Black Caucus, 1992, 2000 (Box 112, Folder 10)
    - Penn State Racism, undated (Box 112, Folder 11)
    - Pittsburgh Council on Intercultural Education, 1947 (Box 112, Folder 12)
    - Pittsburgh Foundation, 1998 (Box 112, Folder 13)
    - Political Trailblazers, 2003 (Box 112, Folder 14)
    - PACE, 1994 (Box 112, Folder 15)
    - Project 90 Inc., 1995 (Box 112, Folder 16)
    - Racial Inequality Education, undated (Box 112, Folder 17)
    - Reinventing Brown v. Board of Education, undated (Box 112, Folder 18)
    - Resumes, undated (Box 112, Folder 19)
    - Riot Fact Finding Committee FOP, 1968 (Box 112, Folder 20)
    - St. Francis, 1992 (Box 112, Folder 21)
    - School Segregation, undated (Box 112, Folder 22)
    - Shooting Star Black Literary Magazine, 1989 (Box 112, Folder 23)
    - Smithsonian, 1979 (Box 112, Folder 24)
    - Speaking Engagement, undated (Box 112, Folder 25)
    - Springer-Kemp, Maida, 2000 (Box 112, Folder 26)
    - SUNY Albany, 1990 (Box 112, Folder 27)
    - Supreme Court, Irvis v. Moose Lodge, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 28)
    - Symposium on the State of States, 1990 (Box 112, Folder 29)
    - Temple University, 1990 (Box 112, Folder 30)
    - Temple University, Center for African American History and Culture, 1987 (Box 112, Folder 31)
    - United Negro College Fund, undated (Box 112, Folder 32)
    - University of Pittsburgh, 1997, 2005 (Box 112, Folder 33)
    - University of Pittsburgh, African American Deans, 2001 (Box 112, Folder 34)
    - University of Pittsburgh, African Heritage Classroom, 1987-1996 (Box 112, Folder 35)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Black Studies Major, undated (Box 112, Folder 36)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Graduate School of Public Health, 1998 (Box 112, Folder 37)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Institute of Politics, 1995 (Box 112, Folder 38)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Kenya Pilot Project, 1986-1989 (Box 112, Folder 39)
    - Urban League, 1997-2003 (Box 112, Folder 40)
    - Urban League Annual Report, 2002-2003 (Box 112, Folder 41)
    - Urban League, Interview, undated (Box 112, Folder 42)
    - Urban League, Ronald H. Brown Banquet & Awards, 1998 (Box 112, Folder 43)
    - Vital Issues, 1991 (Box 112, Folder 44)
    - Western Pennsylvania Black Political Assembly, 1980 (Box 112, Folder 45)
    - Western Pennsylvania Black Political Statement of Accord, undated (Box 112, Folder 46)
    - Zaire-American Research Institute, 1989 (Box 112, Folder 47)
  - Housing (2010 addition), 1973-1999; 8.
    Irvis was interested in providing housing opportunities for all people, regardless of financial ability. The material in this subseries contains research compiled by Irvis concerning housing issues in Pittsburgh and Pennsylvania, articles he authored concerned with the availability of equal-opportunity housing, and legislative material related to the various issues he identified. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Action Housing Inc., 1991 (Box 112, Folder 48)
    - Articles, 1973-1976 (Box 112, Folder 49)
    - Hill House Association, 1985 (Box 112, Folder 50)
    - Irvis Report, 1976-1977 (Box 112, Folder 51)
    - K. Leroy Irvis Towers, 1999 (Box 112, Folder 52)
    - Legislation, 1973-1977 (Box 112, Folder 53)
    - Metropolitan Tenants' Organization of Allegheny County, undated (Box 112, Folder 54)
    - Notes, undated (Box 112, Folder 55)
    - Press Releases, 1973-1976 (Box 112, Folder 56)
    - Report of Financial Status of the Housing Authority of the City of Pittsburgh, 1978 (Box 112, Folder 57)
    - WAMO Radio Show, 1977 (Box 112, Folder 58)
- Campaigns, 1958-1994; VIII.
  This series documents Irvis's own campaigns for the Pennsylvania State House of Representatives as well as his involvement in some of the campaigns of his colleagues in the State House and Senate. The series consists primarily of promotional material (flyers, posters, buttons, fact sheets, etc.) and correspondence, as well as a substantial amount of financial documentation, including donations and expenses.
  The series has been divided into four subseries based on the date the material was acquired by the University of Pittsburgh.
  - Election Campaign (1980 Addition), 1958; 1.
    This subseries includes posters, flyers, correspondence, clippings, notes and literature from Irvis' election campaign, 1958.
    - 1958 (Box 51, Folder 31-33)
    - Miscellaneous Literature (Box 51, Folder 34)
  - Irvis' Campaigns / Committee to Re-elect Irvis, (1995 Addition), 1978-1986; 2.
    This subseries includes correspondence, expense reports, contributions, and other re-election materials relating to campaigns, 1978-1986. These materials are arranged by chronologically by campaign.
    - Committee to Re-elect Irvis, Fundraiser (Box 57, Folder 27)
    - Committee to Re-elect Irvis, Contributions (Box 57, Folder 28)
    - Committee to Re-elect Irvis, Correspondence (Box 57, Folder 29)
    - Committee to Re-elect Irvis, Expenses (Box 57, Folder 30)
    - Campaign Contributions, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 31)
    - Campaign Expenses, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 32)
    - Reappointment Information, 1981 (Box 58, Folder 33)
    - Committee to Re-elect Irvis, Expenses/Donations, 1982 (Box 58, Folder 34-35)
    - Committee to Re-elect Irvis, Contributions, 1982 (Box 58, Folder 36)
    - Committee to Re-elect Irvis, Expenses/Donations, 1983 (Box 58, Folder 37)
    - Committee to Re-elect Irvis, Contributions, 1984 (Box 58, Folder 38)
    - Committee to Re-elect Irvis, Expenses, 1985 (Box 59, Folder 39-40)
    - Committee to Re-elect Irvis, Contributions, 1985 (Box 59, Folder 41)
    - Committee to Re-elect Irvis, Expenses, 1985 (Box 59, Folder 42-43)
    - Committee to Re-elect Irvis, Contributions, 1985 (Box 59, Folder 44)